<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wine | Paul Shaiju]]></title>
  <link href="http://paultsr.in/blog/categories/wine/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://paultsr.in/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-18T22:32:29+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://paultsr.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Run Windows applications on Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://paultsr.in/blog/2013/02/14/run-windows-applications-in-linux/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T16:33:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://paultsr.in/blog/2013/02/14/run-windows-applications-in-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Wine Doors 0.1 &amp; Wine in Ubuntu</h2>

<p>Wine Doors is an application that allows easy installation and managing of Windows application on Linux desktop .</p>

<p>This what Wine Doors Website has to say : -</p>

<p>Wine-doors is an application designed to make installing windows software on Linux, Solaris or other Unix systems easier. Wine-doors is essentially a <em>package management tool</em> for windows software on Linux systems.</p>

<p>Since Wine-Doors is basically to manage applications installed through wine and simplify their installation through wine so installing wine is a must.</p>

<p><strong>To install Wine</strong></p>

<p><code>sudo apt-get install wine</code></p>

<p>After installing wine click <em>here</em> to download the latest version of Wine-Doors(<em>wine-doors_0.1.3rc1_all.deb</em>)</p>

<p>Install the following packages from a terminal</p>

<p><code>sudo apt-get install orange</code></p>

<p><code>sudo apt-get install cabextract</code></p>

<p><code>sudo dpkg -i wine-doors_0.1.3rc1_all.deb</code></p>

<p>I have used wine-doors release candidate 1 .</p>

<p>After completing above steps launch Wine-Doors from <strong>Applications -> System-Tools -> Wine-Doors</strong></p>

<p>Now Wine-Doors would download and install some necessary apps and when all this inital confiuguration is over you would find a dialog like this providing you a easy way of installing a number of popular windows application.</p>

<p>I Was highly impressed by the ease with which it is possible to install many popular application using wine-doors.It was really impressive .There are a lot of windows applications that can be installed by wine.Check the <em>wine site</em> for the new windows applications which it supports.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/wine-doors1.png" title="wine installation on linux image1" ></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/wine-doors3.png" title="wine installation on linux image2" ></p>

<p><em>Wine-Doors in Action</em></p>

<h2>License</h2>

<p>Paul S</p>

<p><em>Free Software Supporter!</em></p>

<p><em>Tested in Ubuntu and JOSS Linux</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
