<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: quotes | Paul Shaiju]]></title>
  <link href="http://paultsr.in/blog/categories/quotes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://paultsr.in/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-23T16:25:27+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://paultsr.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Favourite Quotes]]></title>
    <link href="http://paultsr.in/blog/2013/02/14/rumy-favourite-quotes/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T16:56:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://paultsr.in/blog/2013/02/14/rumy-favourite-quotes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Following are the Quotes which have always inspired me</strong></p>

<p><em>“The most beautiful discovery true friends make is that they can grow separately without growing apart” - Elisabeth Foley</em></p>

<p><em>“Live with Chivalry”</em></p>

<p><em>“Happiness held is the seed. Happiness shared is the flower” - John Harrigan</em></p>

<p><em>“There is a great value in disaste because you can start all over again” - Thomas Edison</em></p>

<p><em>“Doing nothing is very hard to do.. you never know when you're finished” - Leslie Nielson</em></p>

<p><em>“Do not go where the path may lead, go instead where there is no path and leave a trail” - Ralph Waldo</em></p>

<p><em>“Be fearful when others are greedy and Be greedy when others are fearful” - Warren Buffet</em></p>

<p><em>“Great men are eccentric”</em></p>

<p><em>“Live what you love, don't be bored”</em></p>

<p><em>“Dream is not what you see in sleep, dream is the thing which does not let you sleep”</em></p>

<p><em>“Education is when you read the fine print, Experience is what you get if you don’t”</em></p>

<p><em>“I Love you, not for what you are, but for what I am when I am with you”</em></p>

<p><em>“We are what we Love, not what Loves us”</em></p>

<p><em>“Count your age by friends, Count your life by smiles”</em></p>

<p><em>“I am not in this world to live up to your expectations, and you are not in this world to live up to mine.
You are you, and I am I, and if by chance we find each other, it’s beautiful”</em></p>

<p><em>“പൊക്കമില്ലായ്മയാനെന്റെ പൊക്കം” — കുഞ്ഞുണ്ണി മാഷ്</em></p>

<p><em>“ഒരു വളപ്പോട്ടുന്ടെന്‍ കയ്യില്‍ , ഒരു മയില്‍ പീലി ഉണ്ടുള്ളില്‍ , വിരസ നിമിഷങ്ങള്‍ സരസമാക്കനിവ ധാരലമാനെനിക്കെന്നും” — കുഞ്ഞുണ്ണി മാഷ്</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p><em>“If you have an apple and I have an apple and we exchange these apples then you and I will still each have one apple. But if you have an idea and I have an idea and we exchange these ideas, then each of us will have two ideas” –George Bernard Shaw</em></p>

<p><em>“Beauty and color may attract the eye, but only a smile can catch the attention of the hearts”</em></p>

<p><em>“All the beautiful things in life are not seen, nor touched, but are felt in the heart”</em></p>

<p><em>“He who asks a question is a fool for five minutes; he who does not ask a question remains a fool forever”</em></p>

<p><em>“Dream as if you’ll live for ever, live as if you’ll die today” –James Dean</em></p>

<p><em>“We are what we think. All that we are arises with our thoughts” –Budha</em></p>

<p><em>“Making too many friends is not a big thing….!! Only those who having gud character and who understand us will stay for ever…and ever”</em></p>

<h2>License</h2>

<p>Paul S</p>

<p><em>Free Software Supporter!</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
